Sue Ferrara Collection of Baum Research Material
Sue Ferrara Collection of Baum Research Material
1950-1985
Ferrara, Susan.
0.75 linear ft.
Correspondence and printed material related to children's author L. Frank Baum
2750914
Biographical History
Susan Ferrara is a Baum biographer and scholar. She is the author of The Family of the Wizard: the Baums of Syracuse and other books on L. Frank Baum and his work. She attended SUNY-Geneseo, the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, and the University of Maryland College Park. In the past she has worked as a writer/editor for ABC and currently does freelance research and writing.
L. Frank Baum (1856-1919) is a beloved children's author, writer of The Wonderful Wizard of Oz and a plethora of other stories, poems, and scripts. The majority of this collection focuses on his niece, Cynthia Baum Tassini, for whom it is rumored the dedication in the The Emerald City of Oz ("Dedicated to Her Royal Highness Cynthia II of Syracuse") could refer to.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Sue Ferrara Collection of Baum Research Material consists of research material gathered by Susan Ferrara during the course of her work, including correspondence and printed material.
Correspondence consists of incoming mail to Cynthia Baum Tassini.
Printed material contains clippings, books, and microfilm.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged chronologically, with undated material or empty envelopes at the end. Printed material is single items, except for clippings, which are arranged chronologically with undated material at the end.
Related Material
Please for more material related to L. Frank Baum. Some material can also be found in Rare Books by searching.
Subject and Genre Headings
Biography; Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- Children's; Baum, L. Frank (Lyman Frank), 1856-1919.; Baum, Frank Joslyn, 1883-1958.; Tassini, Cynthia Baum.; Wizard of Oz (Fictitious character); Children's literature, American.; Black-and-white photographs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Doctoral dissertations.; Microfilms.; Newsletters.; Photographs.; Research notes.; Authors.; Biographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Sue Ferrara, 2001.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Baum, Frank J., 1950-1958; contains 2 photographs (Box 1)
  - Brody, Ed, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Meyer, Fred M., 1973-1984; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Austin and the Reese River Mining District, 1985; Donald R. Abbe (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1952-1960; undated (Box 1)
  - Columbia Library Columns, May 1955; Vol. 4, No. 3 (Box 1)
  - Exhibition catalog, 1956; Columbia University (Box 1)
  - Keystone Mining Co. Circular, microfilm (Box 2)
  - The Oil Circuit, 1969; dissertation by Bob Herbert Copeland (Box 2)